Didimus Kimbi

Contact

Address

Bridgeport, WV, 26330

Phone

+13017958059

E-mail

kdidimus@ymail.com

Skills

RDBMS

Very Good

Linux Systems

Good

Software Development

Good

Database development

Very Good

Languages

JavaScript

Good

Python

Good

Java

Good

Skilled and well-organized Database specialist with 8 years of expertise and extensive knowledge of software management and development life-cycle. Proficient in diverse a range of scripting and development languages, including SQL, Python, JavaScript and Java. Good communication and documentation skills. Enthusiastic to contribute to team success through hard work, attention to detail and excellent organizational skills. Motivated to learn, grow and excel in software development.

Work History

2018-09 -2021-08

Database Specialist

Department of, Ideal Innovations Inc, Clarksburg, WV

- Windows Server 2014, 2016, RHEL 7.x, 8.x, CentOS 7.6, SQL Server, MongoDB
- Assisted with capacity planning, implementing and documenting SQL Database migration.
- Performed data extraction, transformation and loading (ETL) between systems using SQL tools.
- Experience in Creating Tables, Views, Triggers, Cursors,
 Dynamic Stored Procedures, User Defined Functions and other
 Transact-SQL (DDL, DML) statements for various applications.
- Manage and maintain high volume transactional tables and indexes, database reorganization.
- Experience in Performance tuning, Query Optimization,
 Client/Server Connectivity, Database consistency checks using DBCC utilities.
- Developed user defined functions and triggers to implement the requirements of DISA STIGs.
- Created SQL Server audits and policies to monitor activity on SQL databases to ensure databases were in compliance, and met the Service Level Agreement (SLA) of our clients.
- Safeguarding data by implementing DoD DISA STIGs regulations, managing user access and securing databases.
- Participate in Database efforts for Authority to Operate (ATO) by following the Authorizing Official (AO) directions.
- Deployed builds in Production servers for schema changes and worked in CMR (Change Management Request) department.
- Worked with several teams and lead database team in the process of development of a Disaster Recovery and high availability solutions.
- Configured Database disaster recovery solution; Failover Cluster Instance (FCI) and Availability Groups (AGs

Very Good

- Worked with Clustered environment (Active/Passive) to further increase scalability and stability of organization's critical systems.
- Design, creation, configuration, recovery and support of MongoDB/SQL Server databases & clusters.
- Managing, installing, and, upgrading software packages using YUM and RPM and creating YUM repository files for offline servers.
- Deploy and manage Linux VMs on ESXi server using vSphere client.
- Provide ongoing support on networking services and protocols such as TCP/IP, NIS, DNS, NFS, LDAP, FTP, SSH, SNMP, SSL, and HTTP.
- Install, configure and manage Apache (HTTPD) on Linux production servers.
- Coordinate with Application support, Server Operations,
 Network Operations, Middleware and Database Support teams in
- Build and manage development and QA environment on cloud services (AWS and Azure).
- Troubleshoot issues with VMs running on VMware ESXi 5.5 and 6.0.
- Install, configure and maintain Windows OS versions 2012 R2 (or later), including OS patching, drivers and hardware firmware.
- Installed and configured LDAP servers to authenticate between Linux, Apple and Windows environments.
- Coordinated with project management staff on database development timelines and project scope.

2016-05 - **DBA**

2018-09

FCC, SERCO Inc, Washington

- Sybase 12.X, Postgres 9.2, Oracle 11g 12, MongoDB
- Worked as a member of the DBA team in coordination with seniors and team members.
- Creation of scripts to automate the procedures to generate user statistics.
- Implemented UNIX Scripts using CRONJOB for Day-to-Day activities.
- Worked with developers to address and clarify database request.
- Researching and identifying the related issues.
- Oversee data analysis and database management for Oracle systems including applications upgrades.
- Create and maintain data dictionaries, physical databases and logical database models.

- Monitoring the scheduled backup procedures for daily basis using crontab.
- Automated monitoring databases, backups activities by running CRON JOB and customized various Unix Shell Scripts in sending Email for errors and Logs.
- Design scripts and develop tools to automate periodic task and improve monitoring of system.
- Configuring user creation, their roles and privileges profiles to control access over database objects.
- Involved in database performance monitoring and basic tuning; coordinated with system group on capacity planning at OS level for Oracle instances.
- Database objects Tablespaces, Application Users, Database schemas, profiles, granting privileges and roles.
- Executing ad hoc data requests.
- Manage Instances on Amazon Web Service (AWS) Cloud.
- Tuned databases and application queries, performed server access and login management, and performed database backups and restores.
- Developed administration tools using C, UNIX and Perl shell scripts, and SQL stored procedures to assist DBA's in performing daily functions.
- Implemented and supported Sybase Replication Server to replicate data between remote sites.
- Supported Sybase servers including installation/upgrade, managing user accounts.

Data Analyst/DBA 2017-06 -

CMS, SERCO Inc, Herndon, VA

- Responsible for multiple types of projects including everything from ETL configuration utilizing SSIS packages.
- Data Warehouse integration into our environment.
- Communicating across teams regarding project scope, progress and researching solutions concerning data requests.
- Automate the flow of data to meet requirements for data visualization teams.
- Implement new ways to standardize existing data requests and optimize current workflows.
- Development/support of T-SQL (e.g.
- Stored procedures, views, functions, etc.).
- Participated in collaboration with Senior team members to gather requirements and needs for projects for reporting, data validation

2018-08

- and data manipulation.
- Monitored project progress by tracking activity, resolving problems and recommending actions.
- Works with business analyst to understand their needs and translates business requirements into report designs.
- Design, write, test, and debug database stored procedures and complex queries to extract information.
- Conduct data analysis.
- Prepare, process and upload data sets to Excel Data Connections.
- Integrate data from multiple data sets, analyze and interpret complex data sets and make findings relevant and actionable.

Education

Master of Science: Information Technology, Software Engineering

University of Maryland

Bachelor of Science: Molecular Biology, Biochemistry & Bioinformatics

Towson University - Maryland

Additional Information

Skilled and well-organized computer science graduate with a MS.
 Eager to join your team as a Java developer to help design excellent Web Applications and Web Services. Full stack knowledge of software development from backend services to frontend services. Java development projects with OOP.

Certifications

Security+

CASP

MCSA

OCA